https://www.jgoguen.ca

(650) 646-1809 joel@jgoguen.ca

#### **SUMMARY**

Information Security generalist and software developer with over a decade of experience across a range of Information Security topics. Focus on providing an exceptional user experience while protecting business assets and setting up future success.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Computer Science**

May 2010

University of New Brunswick, Fredericton, NB, Canada

- · Database design
- · Procedural and object-oriented programming
- Software Engineering

### **INTERNSHIPS**

Q1 LABS, INC. Fredericton, NB

# **Software Developer**

April 2007 - November 2008

- Built automated test suite for QRadar remote sensor devices
- Developed QRadar remote sensor devices
- Automated retrieval of new exploit vulnerability information
- Worked on automation of QRadar automatic update packages

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

META PLATFORMS, INC.

MENLO PARK, CA, USA

# **Security Engineer**

March 2018 - Present

- Assess and enhance security of core infrastructure and client laptops and desktops
- Design and develop tools and automation to improve the security of corporate infrastructure and client devices
- Design and develop a system using X.509 client certificates to safeguard access to internal data and systems
- Drove assessment, selection, and implementation of the corporate password manager solution
- Assess the security of new technologies and products and provide recommendations for improvements

# **Production Engineer**

June 2014 - March 2018

- Owned back-end services, infrastructure components, and software code
- Developed capacity plans for scaling up to very large distributed systems
- Work within PCI- and SOX-compliant environments to ensure all changes maintain compliance status
- Document security requirements and decisions and identify future work
- Monitor service health, stability, performance, and security
- Analyze and resolve issues with very large-scale systems
- Evaluate security requirements and assist with identifying tradeoffs
- Drove efforts to overhaul security and access models for automated remediation systems

# System Administrator / Developer

May 2010 - May 2014

- Configured, administered, and maintained the university intranet portal
- Developed a campus map system based on the Google Maps API
- Managed and integrated CAS and Shibboleth Single Sign-On services
- Developed integrations between the university intranet portal and other applications
- Contributed to the development and maintenance of an online university program application system in use by university admissions and prospective students around the world
- Design, develop, and maintain web-based applications and web services with strict privacy and security requirements

- Worked with the Hannon Hill Cascade Content Management System
- Developed Perl and PHP applications to support the needs of the university community
- Worked with the Enterprise Solutions team and the UNB community at large to gather and analyze software requirements
- Analyze and resolve issues with enterprise software, working with departmental experts as required
- Created and maintained internal standards for software development and system administration

Q1 LABS, INC.

FREDERICTON, NB, CANADA

## **Software Developer**

April 2007 - November 2008

- Built automated test suite for QRadar remote sensor devices
- Worked on automation of QRadar automatic update packages
- Automated retrieval of new exploit vulnerability information
- Developed QRadar remote sensor devices

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- · HTML, XML, CSS, JavaScript, and JSON
- · Linux as both client and server
- · macOS and Windows clients
- · Iptables and PF firewalls

- Python and Golang
- OpenBSD servers
- MySQL and PostgreSQL databases
- OpenSSH server

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

- Work unsupervised for extended periods of time
- Work well in a team or independently
- Able to identify work to be done and prioritize execution
- Self-motivated with excellent work ethic